questions = [
    {
        'id': 1,
        'question': 'Which sage, cursed to become a constellation, is associated with the creation of the Sapta Rishi (Ursa Major) in the sky?',
        'options': ['Atri', 'Kashyapa', 'Agastya', 'Vashistha'],
        'answer': 'Vashistha'
    },
    {
        'id': 2,
        'question': 'Who was the father of the demon king Ravana, known for his immense knowledge and power?',
        'options': ['Sumali', 'Kashyapa', 'Vishrava', 'Hiranyaksha'],
        'answer': 'Vishrava'
    },
    {
        'id': 3,
        'question': 'Which Pandava, born through the invocation of the Ashwini Kumaras, was renowned for his unmatched skills in swordsmanship?',
        'options': ['Arjuna', 'Yudhishthira', 'Nakula', 'Sahadeva'],
        'answer': 'Nakula'
    },
    {
        'id': 4,
        'question': 'Which architect was responsible for constructing the magnificent Maya Sabha, known for its illusory design?',
        'options': ['Visvakarma', 'Maya', 'Tvasta', 'Ravana'],
        'answer': 'Maya'
    },
    {
        'id': 5,
        'question': 'Which bird, a devotee of Lord Rama, bravely tried to save Sita during her abduction by Ravana?',
        'options': ['Garuda', 'Shyena', 'Jatayu', 'Sampati'],
        'answer': 'Jatayu'
    },
    {
        'id': 6,
        'question': 'Which king, cursed by sage Agastya, was transformed into the demon Lavanasura?',
        'options': ['Sumali', 'Bali', 'Hayagriva', 'Madhu'],
        'answer': 'Madhu'
    },
    {
        'id': 7,
        'question': 'Which divine physician emerged from the churning of the ocean, bringing with him the knowledge of Ayurveda?',
        'options': ['Chyavana', 'Charaka', 'Dhanvantari', 'Sushruta'],
        'answer': 'Dhanvantari'
    },
    {
        'id': 8,
        'question': 'Which of Krishnaâ€™s wives was the daughter of the bear king Jambavan?',
        'options': ['Rukmini', 'Kalindi', 'Satyabhama', 'Jambavati'],
        'answer': 'Jambavati'
    },
    {
        'id': 9,
        'question': 'Which engineer of the vanara army helped Lord Rama construct the bridge to Lanka?',
        'options': ['Sugriva', 'Nala', 'Vibhishana', 'Hanuman'],
        'answer': 'Nala'
    },
    {
        'id': 10,
        'question': 'Who was the mother of Shani (Saturn), known for her unwavering devotion and intense penance?',
        'options': ['Sanjna', 'Sandhya', 'Chhaya', 'Aditi'],
        'answer': 'Chhaya'
    }
]
